On March 1st, 18 years ago,
Hinazuki was standing alone at this park as always.
It was a little before 6 p.m.
I headed for the hideout back then.
I think I went to get my gloves.
I don't remember whether
I actually found them there.
When I left the hideout and glanced
towards the river bank,
I saw Yuuki-san sitting there, facing the water.
And by the time I took the shortest
route back and passed by the park,
Hinazuki was gone.
Look at the blackboard, class.
A week from now, Hinazuki Kayo will become the
first victim in a serial kidnapping and murder case.
On X-Day.
If I can make sure nothing
happens on March 1st,
and have a birthday party
with Hinazuki the next day,
that will definitely mean
I've changed the future.
I'll erase those crimes from the history books.
Morning, Satoru.
Morning.
Breakfast will be done in a bit.
'Kay.
Thanks for the food.
Hey, Mom.
I want to go out on Saturday.
On a date?
N-No! I thought I might visit the science center with my friends.
Aw, I'd've given you some extra
pocket money if it was a date.
For real?
It's actually a date, ain't it?
Yep.
You should invite her here.
We could have some hot pot or something.
Hinazuki is coming to the birthday party.
Oh, you mean the Hinazukis over on 5th?
Damn, I'm giving her all the answers she wants.
Just be careful when you go.
Thanks.
Now hurry up and eat.
'Kay!
Rise. Bow.
Goodbye!
Doesn't the next Liveman look amazing?!
It does!
What's a "falcon"?
They're like eagles!
Wow, you're so smart.
This Saturday, I'm going to get
Hinazuki out of her house.
Or rather, away from her mother's abuse.
Sensei!
Sen—sei!
What is it?
I don't get this part. Could you explain it?
Let me see.
Ugh, they're so flirty with him.
Didn't you use to be just like them until recently?
Quit being stubborn and join them, yo.
"Yo"? Are you tryin' to act cool?
Crap.
Sensei thinks I'm a thief.
And so do you.
Forget it.
Guys, I've got an idea.
What is it?
Well, why don't we visit the
science center on Saturday?
Hinazuki's coming too.
Sounds goo—
Sorry, Satoru.
There's something I gotta do that day.
O-Oh...
I can't go either, Satoru. I've got
something important to do too.
Y-Yeah. I'd love to go, but I'm busy as well.
S-Same here.
I see...
If you're going with Hinazuki,
you'd be better off without us.
Laters!
Something happen, Fujinuma?
Oh, nothing.
"I told them I can't hang out on Saturday
'cause I've got a date with you."
I told them I can't hang out on Saturday
'cause I've got a date with you.
Should I say that?
I did say that.
But...
my mother told me to come straight home on Saturdays.
I want to take you somewhere.
I'll talk to her for you.
Kenya.
Could you drop by the staff room for a bit?
Absolutely not. I'm not going to allow
two kids to go out on their own.
We're not just going to play.
We'll get to learn things!
You can do that at home.
Saturday's the day Kayo helps me at home.
Helps you? With what?
Releasing your pent-up stress?
I don't see the need to answer that.
Why are you so against her going out?
I can think of several reasons!
You're kids.
Who do you think will have to
take responsibility if something happens?
This bitch has some nerve.
What's wrong with you?
What do you get out of taking this gloomy girl out?
Who cares about that? I just want to save my friend!
Save?
Save Kayo from what?
You think you're some knight in shining armor?
Shit!
I really shouldn't have hinted at her abuse!
How do you feel, Kayo?
You want to go with him?
Get your minds out of the gutter,
you perverted kids!
Mom!
Stop it, Hinazuki-san.
You shouldn't go around calling kids perverted.
Fujinuma-san...
This is none of your business.
Half of it is.
Our kids are motivated about something,
so as their parents, shouldn't we help them out?
I think our families are pretty similar.
Drop by for a chat sometime.
Get inside, Kayo.
Okay.
S-See you on Saturday. It's a promise.
I didn't intrude, did I?
Nah. Thank you.
I got off work early and
just happened to see you kids.
Good thing I followed you.
You were following us?!
I-I was obviously kidding.
Anyway, things should be okay for today.
That girl was wearing surprisingly nice clothes.
It shows that her mother is
conscious about appearances.
Do you know what's going on over there?
Nah.
But after our conversation and looking at her mother, I can make a guess.
That's a former TV news reporter for you.
Kayo's pretty cute, huh?
You're 29 years old! What are you blushing for?!
You'd better not give up just yet.
Of course.
Saturday, February 27th.
It's a clear day.
Looks like Hinazuki's mother has thought
twice about hitting her these past few days.
This guy's my friend.
Are you stupid?
Man, I love this place!
There's hardly anyone around.
It's like we snuck in. Exciting, right?
I hide whenever I see anybody.
Hey, she didn't ask me if I was stupid.
Take a peek into this thing.
Wanna see the planetarium? It's just about to start.
I got my fill of stars the other night.
I guess...
I need to run to the bathroom.
Okay. I'll be around.
What is this feeling?
Déjà vu?
I did come here often,
but never with Hinazuki.
Hinazuki...
Fujinuma.
Thanks for inviting me today.
Did you know I liked this place too?
Did I know?
Is that why I chose this place?
Do aspiring comic artists...
tend to come to places like this?
I remember having the same
conversation 18 years ago.
I came here by myself and ran into Hinazuki.
What is it?
N-Nothing. You think there's a connection?
Am I just repeating the past?
I've been trying to change the future.
Have I been unwittingly following the same path?
Hinazuki!
I'll hold your coat for you.
You sure?
I've already changed a bunch
of things with my actions.
I know that I can change the future.
Fujinuma.
I'm glad I mustered up the courage to come.
Me too.
Satoru.
Hinazuki.
Hey there!
I got done early, so I came.
Sorry we're late.
See? It changed.
Are we interrupting?
Of course not.
Right, Hinazuki?
Right.
Wow, Satoru's such a gentleman!
Good morning!
Morning, Fujinuma.
Oh, morning, Hinazuki.
Thank goodness.
It's Monday, but she's here on time.
Such a pretty face...
I said that out loud.
D-Did you hear that?!
Whoa!
Satoru's got guts!
Are you gonna get married?!
Don't be stupid! They gotta get engaged first!
Get what?
Congrats!
We're starting morning homeroom.
Hinazuki will be murdered tomorrow...
on March 1st.
The real battle starts now.
Laters, Hiromi!
See you tomorrow!
Hey, Hinazuki.
I'll come pick you up tomorrow.
Let's walk to school together.
Sure.
Oh, Mom...
Good evening.
See you tomorrow, then.
I'll come pick you up in the morning.
I'm off!
Okay!
I left home a bit early.
March 1st, 1988.
The day Hinazuki disappeared 18 years ago.
Good morning.
But today will be different.
Morning, Fujinuma.
Morning.
Hinazuki won't be going anywhere.
We're off.
The circumstances now are
quite different from 18 years ago.
Satoru's got guts!
Hinazuki was targeted because she
was always by herself at that park.
Well, you guys better come tomorrow!
Yeah.
Of course.
That's no longer the case as of a few days ago.
Hey, let's go to the kids' center.
And I'm with her today.
I want to go home early today.
Come on, hang out with me.
Okay.
Everything will be all right.
I win again.
You're good!
Okay, maybe not everything.
Hey, Fujinuma. I want to go home now.
Sure, I guess.
It's snowing.
I'll come pick you up tomorrow, too!
See you tomorrow!
'Kay.
I said it as loud as I could.
So that Hinazuki, her mother inside,
and anybody who might've been
listening nearby got the message.
That I'm right here.
X-Day is almost over.
Is this really it?
I'm such an idiot.
Why the hell did I come here?
I did it!
I definitely changed history today.
Morning, Mom.
Huh? It's not even 6 a.m. yet!
I'm off.
What about breakfast?
I didn't sleep a wink after that.
I just wanted to see Hinazuki as soon as possible.
Morning, Hinazuki.
Are you stupid?
You guys are free now, right?
You know it!
We're gonna party at your place.
Then let's go shopp—
Hey, Satoru and Kayo.
I need you to help me with something.
Why today of all days?
Oh, well.
It's probably cause we messed up
while on duty the other day.
Probably.
Man, this is heavy.
Did they seriously not wait for us?
That's ice cold.
That'll be 5,000 yen.
Got it.
Come to think of it, the bill was
exactly 5,000 yen 18 years ago too.
I was so excited about my birthday
that I used up every penny I had.
I think my mother and I made a ton
of sandwiches and ate them by ourselves.
I'm home.
One, two...
Satoru! Hinazuki!
Happy birthday!
Y-You planned all this in secret?
They said they wanted to do this,
so I gave 'em a hand.
Don't tell me...
Is that why we had to help after school?
Yeah, we asked Yashiro-sensei.
He told us it was Hinazuki's birthday too.
Well, we just wanted to surprise you a bit.
It worked!
Oh, the cakes? Satoru insisted we get two.
Sorry, Fujinuma.
I couldn't finish your present in time.
You were working on something?
Yeah...
Oh, so that's why she wanted
to leave so badly yesterday.
I almost had it done last night, but I fell asleep.
Don't worry.
You can give it to me later.
All right, guys.
Let's make sandwiches with
5,000 yen's worth of ingredients!
What? You used up all the money?
Making sandwiches in a big group was a lot of fun.
Unlike 18 years ago, we finished them all in one day.
It's fun having friends.
Hinazuki and I got a lot of presents from everyone.
And...
Open it.
Thank you, Fujinuma.
All of you, too. Thank you so much.
We'll clean up.
You walk Hinazuki home.
It's c-c-cold.
Are you stupid?
B-Bye.
Here.
I'm glad I became friends with you and the others.
Thanks for today.
I'll give you your present tomorrow.
That's a promise.
Okay. It's a promise.
Good night.
Yes!
I did it!
I made it through!
I changed history!
The guys were gone by the time I got home.
With my fatigue from the past
two days reaching its limit,
and my mind being freed from all the tension,
I instantly collapsed into bed and slept like a log.
Damn, I'm late!
Good morning!
Oh, Satoru.
Not late, then.
S-Safe...
So Kayo's the only one who's late.
The day after our birthday,
Hinazuki didn't come to school.
The promise we made at the end...
was never fulfilled.